# Benjamin D. Killeen

Ph.D. Student, Johns Hopkins University Department of Computer Science 3400 N Charles St Baltimore, MD 21218, USA killeen@jhu.edu

😭 benjamindkilleen.com - 🚢 arcade.cs.jhu.edu - 🚢 cirl.lcsr.jhu.edu 🕿 Benjamin D. Killeen - 📵 0000-0003-2511-7929 - 🗘 benjamindkilleen 🎔 @bdkilleen - 🛅 benjamindkilleen - 🔟 @benjamindkilleen

## Summary

A Ph.D. Student at Johns Hopkins University, I am interested in intelligent surgical systems that improve patient outcomes. My recent work involves realistic simulation of interventional X-ray imaging for the purpose of developing Al-integrated surgical systems. I am a member of the Advanced Robotics and Computationally Augmented Environments (ARCADE) research group and the Computational Interaction and Robotics Laboratory (CIRL).

#### Education

Ph.D., Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2019 - present With Mathias Unberath and Gregory D. Hager.

B.A., Computer Science with Honors, Minor in Physics, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. 09/2015 - 06/2019 Thesis: Starting from Scratch: Deep Learning for Novel Scientific Image Analysis With Gordon Kindlmann.

#### Academic Experience

Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. 08/2020 - present With Mathias Unberath, Gregory D. Hager. Research Assistant, Laboratory for Computational Sensing and Robotics, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, 08/2019 - 06/2020

MD, USA. With Gregory D. Hager, Mathias Unberath, and Russel Taylor.

Recipient: LCSR Fellowship for Outstanding Incoming Ph.D. Students. Research assistant, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. With Gordon Kindlmann.

## Professional Experience

Computer Vision / Al Intern, Applied Research, Intuitive Surgical Inc., Sunnyvale, CA, USA. 06/2020 - 07/2020 06/2018 - 08/2018 Software Development Intern, Cognitive Computing, Epic Systems, Verona, WI, USA. Research Intern, IBM Research - Almaden, San Jose, CA, USA. 06/2017 - 08/2017 With Geoffrey Burr.

### Selected Honors

Runner-up, Physics of Medical Imaging Best Student Paper Award 02/2022 For paper [C-5] at SPIE Medical Imaging 2022. 10/2021 Best Paper Award in Bioengineering For paper [C-4] at IEEE BIBE 2021.

04/2021 **Best Presentation Award** In Reliable Software Systems at Johns Hopkins University.

05/2020 Best Graduate Project Award In Computer Integrated Surgical Systems and Technology II at Johns Hopkins University.

04/2020 COVID-19 Dataset Award, Kaggle For the dataset in [M-1].

Intuitive Surgical Best Project Award. For Enriching Unsupervised Feature Learning via Intermediate Subtasks in Deep Learning at Johns Hopkins University.

## Services and Leadership

Academic Services

President, LCSR Graduate Student Association at Johns Hopkins University. 08/2022 - present Organizes social events like First Monday Bagels, Climbing Night, Hydro Lab Happy Hour, and Ice Skating

Established an executive board, annual operating budget, and election process.

Sports Officer, MICCAI Society Student Board.

12/2021 - present

12/2019

03/2018 - 08/2019

	Head of Student Resources, LCSR Graduate Student Committee at Johns Hopkins University.	09/2020 - 08/2022
Community	Family Member, Thread, Baltimore, MD, USA.  Volunteer Instructor, CompileHer, Chicago, IL, USA.	06/2021 - 2022 2019
Peer Review	- IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)	2023
	- International Symposium on Medical Robotics (ISMR)	2023
	- International Conference on Information Processing in Computer-Assisted Interventions (IPCAI)	2023
	- MICCAI Educational Challenge	2022
	- Medical Image Analysis	2022
	- IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	2021-2022
	- Nature Scientific Data	2020
Supervision		
Graduate Students	Han Zhang, Masters, Johns Hopkins Unviersity, Baltimore, MD, USA.	01/2023 - present
	Qiyuan Wu, Masters, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.	08/2022 - present
	<b>Zidi Tao</b> , Research Assistant, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.  Now a PhD student at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute.	10/2021 - 06/2022
	<b>Shreya Chakraborty</b> , Masters, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.  Now at PathAI.	08/2020 - 09/2021
	<b>Philipp Nikutta</b> , Visiting Masters, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany.  Now at Argo Al.	12/2019 - 03/2020
Undergraduates	Sambhav Chordia, Bachelors, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.	06/2022 - 12/2022
	Sean Sebastian Darcy, Bachelors, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA.  Now an incoming PhD student at California Institute of Technology.	10/2021 - 10/2022
	<b>Nethra Venkatayogi</b> , Bachelors, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX, USA.  Now an incoming PhD student with Muyinatu Bell.	05/2021 - 10/2021
	Max Judish, Bachelors, Brown University, Providence, RI, USA.	01/2021 - 08/2021
Projects	Recreating Pelvic Trauma Surgery in Virtual Reality for the Development of Novel C-arm Interfaces. Han Zhang, Zixuan Liu, Liam Wang. Computer Integrated Surgery II, Johns Hopkins Unviersity.  Real-time Integration of 2D-3D Pelvic Registration with Robotic X-ray Acquisition Jiaming Zhang, Zhangcong She. Computer Integrated Surgery II, Johns Hopkins Unviersity.	2023 2023
	3D Segmentation of Hard and Soft Tissue for Simulating X-ray Image Formation with Deep Learning.  Qiyuan Wu, Zhiyuan Ding, Sean Darcy. Computer Integrated Surgery II, Johns Hopkins University.	2022
Assistant Teaching	Computer Integrated Surgery, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. With Russ Taylor. Wrote supplementary course material, led weekly office hours, and taught regular discussion sections.	Fall 2022
	Computer Integrated Surgery, Department of Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD,	Fall 2021
	USA. With Russ Taylor and Emad Boctor.	
	Held weekly office hours and biweekly discussion sections. Managed grading together with Maia Stiber.	
	Machine Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis, Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA. With Yali Amit. Wrote supplementary course material and held weekly lab sessions. Graded coursework.	Spring 2019
	Selected review: "Ben was incredibly patient during office hours and always responsive to student questions. In addition, he often presented demos during office hours or showed easier ways to handle the homework assignments; both were very helpful."  More reviews available at benjamindkilleen.com/teaching/2019-spring-lsda	
Teaching Services	Course assistant. Department of Computer Science, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA - Scientific Visualization	01/2019 - 08/2019

- Scientific Visualization

- Introduction to Computer Science I

J-5

]-4

1-3

1-2

1-1

C-5

C-4

(-3)

C-2

C-1

M-2

M-1

P-1

2020

## **Tutoring in Computer Science, Machine Learning**, Baltimore, MD, USA. Worked with middle and high school students.

#### **Publications**

I have first- (co-) authored 5 (4) peer-reviewed papers and 2 preprints. My publication list is also available on Google Scholar. (\*) denotes equal contribution.

Peer-reviewed Journal Articles

- **B.D. Killeen**, C. Gao, K. Oguine, S. Darcy, M. Armand, R.H. Taylor, G. Osgood, M. Unberath. An Autonomous X-ray Image Acquisition and Interpretation System for Assisting Percutaneous Pelvic Fracture Fixation. To appear in International Journal of Computer Assisted Radiology and Surgery, 2023.
- C. Gao, **B.D. Killeen**, Y. Hu, R.B. Grupp, R.H. Taylor, M. Armand, M. Unberath. SyntheX: Scaling Up Learning-based X-ray Image Analysis Through In Silico Experiments. To appear in Nature Machine Intelligence, 2023. arXiv:10.48550/arXiv.2206.06127.
- **B. D. Killeen**, J. Winter, W. Gu, A. Martin-Gomez, R. H. Taylor, G. Osgood, M. Unberath. Mixed reality interfaces for achieving desired views with robotic X-ray systems. Computer Methods in Biomechanics and Biomedical Engineering: Imaging & Visualization, 7 Dec. 2022, pp. 1-6, doi: 10.1080/21681163.2022.2154272. Special issue: Augmented Environments for Computer Assisted Interventions (AE-CAI) 2022.
- A. Hundt, **B. Killeen**, H. Kwon, C. Paxton, GD Hager. "Good Robot!": Efficient Reinforcement Learning for Multi-Step Visual Tasks with Sim to Real Transfer. IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, vol. 5, no. 4, pp. 6724–6731, Oct. 2020. doi: 10.1109/LRA.2020.3015448.
- S. Ambrogio, P. Narayanan, H. Tsai, R. M. Shelby, I. Boybat, C. di Nolfo, S. Sidler, M. Giordano, M. Bodini, N. Farinha, **B. Killeen**, C. Cheng, Y. Jaoudi, G. W. Burr. Equivalent-accuracy accelerated neural-network training using analogue memory. Nature, vol. 558, no. 7708, p. 60, Jun. 2018. doi: 10.1038/s41586-018-0180-5.

Peer-reviewed Conference Papers

- B. D. Killeen, Shreya Chakraborty, Greg Osgood, Mathias Unberath. Toward perception-based anticipation of cortical breach during K-wire fixation of the pelvis. Medical Imaging 2022: Physics of Medical Imaging. SPIE. doi: 10.1117/12.2612989.
- Runner-up, SPIE Medical Imaging Physics of Medical Imaging Best Student Paper Award
- J. D. Opfermann\*, **B. D. Killeen**\*, C. Bailey, M. Khan, A. Uneri, K. Suzuki, M. Armand, F. Hui, A. Krieger\*\*, M. Unberath\*\*. Feasibility of a Cannula-mounted Piezo Robot for Image-guided Vertebral Augmentation: Toward a Low Cost, Semi-autonomous Approach. 2021 IEEE 21st International Conference on Bioinformatics and Bioengineering (BIBE), Kragujevac, Serbia, 2021 pp. 1-8. doi: 10.1109/BIBE52308.2021.9635356.
- \*Joint first authors; \*\* joint last authors.
- Honored with Best Paper Award in Bioengineering.
- X. Liu\*, **B. D. Killeen\***, A. Sinha, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Neighborhood Normalization for Robust Geometric Feature Learning. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, 2021.
- C. Gao, X. Liu, W. Gu, **B. D. Killeen**, M. Armand, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Generalizing Spatial Transformers to Projective Geometry with Applications to 2D/3D Registrationc. MICCAI, 2020, arxiv:2003.10987.
- X. Liu, Y. Zhang, **B. Killeen**, M. Ishii, G. Hager, R. Taylor, M. Unberath. Extremely Dense Point Correspondences using a Learned Feature Descriptor. Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, pp. 4847-4856, 2020.

Preprints

- J. Y. Wu\*, **B. D. Killeen**\*, P. Nikutta, M. Thies, A. Zapaishchykova, S. Chakraborty, M. Unberath. Changes in Reproductive Rate of SARS-CoV-2 Due to Non-pharmaceutical Interventions in 1,417 U.S. Counties. medRxiv preprint, Jun. 2020, doi: 10.1101/2020.05.31.20118687.
- **B. D. Killeen\***, J. Y. Wu**\***, K. Shah, A. Zapaishchykova, P. Nikutta, A. Tamhane, S. Chakraborty, J. Wei, T. Gao, M. Thies, M. Unberath. A County-level Dataset for Informing the United States' Response to COVID-19. arXiv preprint, 2020, arXiv:2004.00756.

Patents

G. W. Burr and **B. D. Killeen**. 2020. Efficient Processing of Convolutional Neural Network Layers Using Analog-memory-based Hardware. 20200117986, filed March 25, 2019, and issued April 16, 2020, uspto.report/patent/app/20200117986.

## Selected Press

- Dziarkach, Andrei. "Details with Andrei Dziarkach." Voice of America. November 21, 2020 Accessed November 26, 2020. golosameriki.com/a/detali/5671254.html.
- Rosen, Jill. "Dog Training Methods Help JHU Teach Robots to Learn New Tricks." The Johns Hopkins University Hub. The Johns Hopkins University, October 26, 2020. hub.jhu.edu/2020/10/26/positive-reinforcement-for-robots

### Selected Coursework

Graduate

Vision as Bayesian Inference Reliable Software Systems Theory of Computation Parallel Programming Nonlinear Optimization II Computer Integrated Surgery II

Computer Integrated Surgery I

GPA: 3.82

Undergraduate Unsupervised Learning\*

Computer Vision

 $\dot{\rm Machine}$  Learning and Large Scale Data Analysis

Operating Systems Honors Combinatorics Honors Algorithms Honors Discrete Mathematics

Scientific Visualization
Programming Languages

Networks and Distributed Systems Quantum Mechanics I \& II Intermediate Mechanics

Electronics Wizards

\*Graduate level.

Memberships International Society for Optics and Photonics (SPIE) Student Member

Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) Graduate Student Member

Extracurricular Outside of the office, I enjoy bouldering, cycling, and running. I also write creatively:

Creative nonfiction: benjamindkilleen.com/blog

Science fiction.

Metadata This document is available

- online: benjamindkilleen.com/markdown-cv.

- as a PDF: benjamindkilleen.com/files/cv.pdf.

Created based on markdown-cv by Eliseo Papa with styles based on David Whipp.

MIT License.

Last updated: March 2023

GPA: 3.81